# **EUGENE HALPIN**

Wendell, NC 27591

Phone: 315-263-2128 | Email: ejhalpin3@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/eugene-halpin | Github: https://github.com/ejhalpin | Portfolio:

https://ejhalpin.github.io

#### SUMMARY

Full stack web developer with a background in physics and object oriented programming. Passionate about engineering quality solutions to complex real-world problems. Keen eye for detail and a grounded aesthetic centered on the user experience. Enjoy working on a team with dedicated members and sharing knowledge and experience. Leadership and increasing responsibility are strong motivators.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL, JSON, JSX, Java

**Libraries/Frameworks:** NodeJS, ExpressJS, ReactJS, jQuery, Bootstrap, Google Cloud **Databases:** MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase Realtime Database, Google Cloud Storage

Tools/Technologies: Git, Firebase Authentication, Handlebars, Local and Session Storage, Cookies

#### **P**ROJECTS

## Poker App |

https://github.com/adishthapa/UNCBootcamp-Project03 | https://warm-garden-85112.herokuapp.com/

A Texas Hold-em Poker app that allows players connect and play against one another. This game fully incorporates the nuanced rules of Texas Hold-em cash games including side-pots, buttons, and blinds while also allowing users to chat and modify their profile.

- Served as project lead; engineered game logic, built the API routes to serve up game data and drive user gameplay experience, backend design of SocketIO events, UX design
- Utilizes a host of technologies including NodeJS, ExpressJS, ReactJS, MongoDB, Mongoose, Auth0 and SocketIO

## Busy Bee | https://github.com/ejhalpin/Project2 | https://busy-bee-home.herokuapp.com/

A powerful full stack home maintenance and task management system designed to connect users and provide for easy workflow management in the home. The app allows users to link accounts, create, assign and view tasks on a daily, weekly, monthly, and yearly scale, and contribute to a community board of Q/A and helpful DIY conversations.

- Served as project lead; developed API routes, database models, and engineered custom authentication using core node crypto methods. Designed UI/UX, built custom calendars and views for the task creation and display modals, connected with email service to verify user accounts and deliver notifications.
- Utilizes a host of technologies including NodeJS, Express, MySQL, Sequelize, SendGrid, Crypto, MomentJS, and Axios

## Recipe Box | https://github.com/frostyasian/Project1 | https://ejhalpin.github.io/Project1/

A one stop location for recipe searching and collecting designed for those who like to scour the web for recipes and keep them in one place. This application uses powerful APIs to deliver recipes based on keyword searches and a cloud-based storage model.

- Served as project leader; implemented user authentication, developed UI/UX, collaboration through GitHub
- Git, Google Cloud Services (Firebase, Firebase Authentication), HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript/jQuery

#### EXPERIENCE

**Mentor and Team Lead** 2014 - 2018 FIRST Robotics

Minneapolis, MN

Coached and mentored high school students in the design, fabrication, and coding of a robot for regional competition.

#### Key Accomplishments:

- Upheld the principles and values of FIRST, including cooperation and innovation
- Introduced new technologies to the team including 3D printing and CAD
- Instructed team on mechanical, electrical, and software engineering and design best practices
- Successfully developed a lasting business partnership with Medtronic while growing a community of FIRST teams, their students and parents.

# **Adjunct Faculty Saint Thomas University**

2017 - 2018

Saint Paul, MN

Developed curriculum for integrated lab/lecture environment. Incorporated regular recurring formative and summative assessments to assess student confidence and success.

#### Key Accomplishments:

- Developed lasting relationships with students
- Integrated new technology into the classroom and developed systems to maintain existing technology
- Acted as department liaison on a special project to solve network and printing issues in classrooms

#### Interim Employment

2014 - 2017

Several positions (outlined below) were held as I searched for opportunities that would lead to a career. In each of the positions below I consistently took on increased responsibility while meeting expectations and building professional relationships with colleagues.

- Assistant Manager in Training / Warehouse Technician, Frattalone's Ace Hardware, Saint Paul, MN 2016-17
- Physical Science Teacher, Ramsey Middle School, Saint Paul, MN 2015-16
- Physics and Environmental Science Teacher, FAIR School Downtown, Minneapolis, MN 2014-15

## **Instructor & Lab Coordinator Virginia Tech Physics Department**

2010 - 2014

Blacksburg, VA

Developed curriculum for introductory physics lectures. Worked as an active member of the instructional team to elevate teaching techniques and enhance course content. Managed a team of 50 graduate students from multiple disciplines and backgrounds, acting in a train-the-trainer role for laboratory instruction. Served as the department single-point-of-contact for 2500+ undergraduate students enrolled in introductory physics labs.

## Key Accomplishments:

- Improved and maintained the physics department laboratory online portal
- Managed confidential records for all enrolled undergraduate students
- Developed grading strategies to ensure consistency across lab sections
- Worked closely with the lab manager to maintain existing lab equipment and purchase new equipment
- Developed, tested, and published new labs for the introductory lab curriculum.

### **EDUCATION**

### Bootcamp Certificate: UNC CHapel Hill, Raleigh, NC

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, HandelbarsJS & ReactJS.

MS, Physics: Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, VA BA, Physics: SUNY Potsdam, Potsdam, NY